levi.com 2016-06-20

# Privacy Policy - Levi Strauss

This online Privacy Policy was last updated on  **January 29, 2014**.

Levi Strauss & Co. (LS&CO) is deeply committed to the relationship of trust we have with you — our consumers. For more than 155 years we have been creating authentic products by leading with our values. As we continue to innovate in how we bring our products to life online, we’ll match cutting-edge technology with your privacy interests.

**OUR PILLARS OF PRIVACY**

**Transparency**

We want you to know what and how information is collected when you interact with our websites.

**Choice**

We will offer you choices about how your information can be used by us and our trusted business partners.

**Data Integrity**

We will take reasonable precautions to protect information we collect about you on our websites through the use of secure technologies.

**_What Information Do We Collect?_**

**Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”)**

****Any information that can be used to identify you is considered personally identifiable information or PII. This includes your name, physical address, e-mail, phone number, fax number, and credit card information.

**Browsing Information**

Information we collect about your activities on our websites through the use of technology such ascookies and web beacons is referred to as browsing information. This browsing information is linked to an anonymous IP identifier and not to you personally. If for any reason your browsing information is linked to information that can personally identify you, we’ll treat it as PII.

**Information You Post**

****All information that you share about yourself, whether PII or not, in a public open forum – on a social network, in user-generated content elements of our websites, etc. — will be considered public information for the purposes of this policy. If you don’t want it to be public, don’t post it.

**_Who Collects Information?_**

We collect information from you when you interact with our websites. We may also collect information about you from third parties. Our trusted business partners also collect information from you on our behalf in the course of helping us operate our websites and provide services of interest to you. Any reference to “we” or “us” may also refer to our trusted business partners. We also permitthird-party advertising companies to collect your browsing information as well to provide ads on our behalf that are tailored to your interests. [Click here](http://privacy.levistrauss.com/privacy/#3browseInfo) for more information on interest based ads and your choices regarding your information.

When you interact with our websites information may be collected in several different ways. It may be collected in obvious, active ways, such as when you provide your name and address or other information when making a purchase in a store or online, when using the customer service chat feature, when you enter a contest or sweepstakes or if you upload a photo or product review to our site. It may also be collected passively or automatically when you visit and move around on our websites through the use of cookies and web beacons that capture your browsing information to enable us and third-party advertising companies to better tailor content and advertising to you.[Click here](http://privacy.levistrauss.com/privacy/#6defCookies) for more information about how cookies and web beacons work.

In general, collection of your PII, browsing information and information you post or provide may vary across our stores and websites depending on their purpose, functionality or unique aspects.

**_Use and Sharing of Collected Information_**

We use information collected on our websites for four primary purposes.

  * First, we use information collected to facilitate your online shopping and to offer you information and promotional material about the products and services you see on our websites.
  * Second, we use your browsing information to help us analyze our websites, services and offerings. We consider such information analytics data.
  * Third, your browsing and shopping information is used to provide you with interest-based advertising. .
  * Fourth, we may use information you post in public areas to provide you with an interactive social media experience that brings aspects of your social networking community to our websites.

We may share your PII within our family of companies under common ownership; we do not share your PII with third parties for marketing purposes or other than as described in this privacy statement. Any trusted business partner receiving PII is contractually prohibited from discussing, disclosing or making any use of such PII except as directly necessary to provide us with the services for which we have contracted. We will get your consent first if at any time we would like to share your PII with other third parties for marketing purposes.

**Cookies**

A “cookie” is a computer file that acts as an identification card for your computer. When you visit our sites, unique cookies are placed on your browser. The purpose of the cookie is to distinguish your browser from all other browsers that visit our sites. However, by recognizing your browser, we can serve you better. For example, the cookies allow us to hold the selections in your shopping cart when you navigate away from the order page and then return to complete the order; because of the cookie, you don’t have to start over with your shopping. We can also keep track of what pages of our website your browser visited and whether you purchased a product. That way we can measure such things as how effective our advertising campaigns have been. Working with third-party advertising companies, the use of cookies also enables us to provide you with customized banner ads that we think will be more useful than randomly-generated ads because they are based on your past purchases and page visits to our sites.

**Web Beacons**

When you visit our ecommerce sites, web beacons will recognize specific cookies that have been placed on your browser. Web beacons can convey information that a browser with a recognized cookie has accessed a page or a certain part of a page on our website, depending on where the web beacon is located on the website. For example, a web beacon located on our purchase confirmation page will record that a browser with a recognized cookie accessed that page which means that we can conclude that the browser was used to purchase a product. The web beacon does not, however, tell us that you specifically (by reference to PII) have purchased a product because the cookie is only the browser’s identification card; it is not your personal identification card.

We use web beacons to measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns and to improve our websites by recognizing which pages are visited and whether those visits result in purchases. Web beacons also allow third-party advertising companies we work with to select and serve banner advertisements to your browser that you would be most likely to be interested in.

**Trusted Business Partners**

We work with industry-leading business partners who help us operate our websites and provide important services to our customers and visitors. Our business partners may change over time but we are committed to building relationships with third parties who are dedicated to providing you a safe and satisfying experience on our websites. Our trusted business partners are contractually obligated to collect and use any information collected from you on an LS&CO site or on behalf of LS&CO in a manner that is consistent with this privacy policy.

**Third-Party Advertising Companies**

We allow certain companies to collect information from browsers of our websites to use to serve interest-based ads. These companies are usually third party ad servers, ad agencies, technology vendors or providers of sponsored content. Using cookies and web beacons, these companies collect data from a particular browser about web viewing behaviors over time and across unrelated websites and use such data to predict user preferences and to deliver advertisements to that browser which are calculated to target that browser’s predicted preferences.

**Analytics Data**

Information collected through cookies and web beacons to keep track of what products you viewed and purchased and what areas or pages you viewed on our websites is called “analytics data”. We use analytics data to improve the design and content of our websites, to help us learn things like what pages are most attractive to all of our visitors and what promotions visitors like to see, and to gauge the success of our advertising campaigns.

**Interest-Based Advertising**

Interest-based advertising has become commonplace across the Web. It is the term we use for the activity that enables us to tailor ads to your interests and activities. Either LS&CO or third-party advertising companies we work with may look at your browsing activity, such as the types of content you access, ads you click on, and searches you conduct. We can then infer certain interests you have and place ads and offer you deals that meet your needs. Our goal for interest-based advertising is to show ads to people likely to be interested in the products we offer at LS&CO. [Click Here](http://privacy.levistrauss.com/privacy/#3) to learn more about our practices with regard to interest-based ads.

******Friend’s Store**

The Friend’s Store is a section on our levi.com website, offered in partnership with Facebook, that allows you to share the products you like with your friends and find out what they “like”. If you interact with our Friends Store or click on the Like button on our levi.com website, you will essentially be using our website and Facebook at the same time but your “Friends” experience will be governed by the privacy and other policies of Facebook.

We keep your PII confidential, and we require, by contract, that each of our trusted business partners who may have access to any such PII information keep it confidential as well. Our trusted business partners, in turn, may share information with their own service providers pursuant to similar confidentiality restrictions.

We will not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer any of your PII to any other outside parties without getting your consent first. “Outside parties” do not include companies owned by LS&CO or our trusted business partners who help operate and provide services on our websites.

Of course, to the extent we reasonably believe that a disclosure is required by law, to enforce our website policies, or to protect your or others’ rights, property or safety, we reserve the right to do so.

**Safeguarding Your PII**

When you register at our sites, we ask you to set up a password that you can use to access your information at our sites. If you want to cancel your password or change it, or something happens to your password, click on the “Contact Us” link found in the Help/Customer Service sections of our websites.

We use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt transmissions of sensitive information from your computer to our servers. However, when you communicate with customer service via email or chat on our websites, these communications are handled via unsecured transmissions. Please be aware that information provided (such as email address, payment information, etc.) may be accessible to others. For that reason we ask that you protect yourself and not share sensitive information via these communication channels.

**Contact Us Regarding Your Information**

If you have any questions or concerns about Levi Strauss & Co.’s Online Privacy Policy, please send an email to MBXLSAprivacy@levi.com; call us Toll-Free at 1-866-290-6064; or write to us at:

Levi Strauss & Co.  
General Counsel  
1155 Battery Street  
San Francisco, CA 94111

******Online Updates to the Privacy Policy**

If we modify this Privacy Policy, we will post the revised Privacy Policy on this website. We also may post a notice on this website or send an email describing the changes if the policy changes in any material way. You should check this website regularly to see if any recent changes to this Privacy Policy have occurred.

**Your PII**

With your PII — like the information you give us to fulfill an order or sign up for an online offer or contest – we will always give you the right to change or correct your information and the choice of not hearing from us again. There are several ways you can control our use of any submitted PII in connection with promotional communications.

When you set up an account, or either click on “My Account” from any page or “Manage Your Account” from within the Help Desk area of one of our websites, you can access, correct or update your choices/settings.

If you receive email communications from us on behalf of any of our brands and want to opt out of receiving such communications in the future from that brand, you can opt out by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the promotional email or by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” button at the bottom of any of that brand’s websites.

If you have any difficulty managing your communication preferences, please email [MBXLSAprivacy@levi.com](mailto:MBXLSAprivacy@levi.com).

**Your Browsing Information**

We work with third-party advertising companies that may collect your browsing and shopping information in order to provide LS&CO and other advertisements of interest to you. We refer to this practice as interest-based advertising. We believe these interest-based ads are more useful to you than randomly-generated ads because they are tailored to your shopping and product interests as indicated by your browsing habits.

If you would like to learn more about interest-based advertising and see what choices you may have about how companies use your information, please go to <http://aboutads.info/choices/> or <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>. We do not operate or control these sites, and are not responsible for the opt-out choices available there. The only way to fully opt-out of online tracking is to adjust your browser settings to reject cookies or to notify you when a cookie is set. Please remember, even if you opt-out of interest-based advertising on or through [http://aboutads.info](http://aboutads.info/) you may still receive ads from LS&CO, as interest-based ads are only one form of advertising.

Finally, it is important to note that in most cases opting out drops an “opt-out cookie” on your browser. As a result, if you delete, block or otherwise restrict cookies or use a different computer or Internet browser, you’ll need to renew your opt-out choice.

**Controlling Cookies**

Because cookies and web beacons are the technology generally driving collection of browsing information, you can also block cookies to control data collection related to interest-based advertising. You can typically do so through your Internet browser. For instructions, check your browser’s technical information. Preventing your browser from accepting cookies prevents the collection of your browsing information for purposes of delivering interest-based ads. However, it may also disable or interfere with shopping features on our sites and other sites that you may visit. For example, cookies allow us to hold your shopping cart selections when you navigate away and then return to the order page. Cookies also allow us to recognize you as an account holder when you return to our sites. Most browsers accept cookies automatically. We recommend that you leave cookies “turned on” so we can offer you a better shopping experience on our sites.

**Interacting with Social Media on our Websites**

Social Media provides tools that many of our customers use and enjoy, and we include links to various social media platforms on our websites. If you interact with these social media tools through our websites, your experience on those social media sites will be governed by the privacy and other policies of those sites. So, the privacy settings you have chosen on those sites will determine the degree to which your information is made public. We encourage you to choose your privacy settings on those sites accordingly.
